<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bayme.sh Home on Bayme.sh</title><link>https://bayme.sh/</link><description>Recent content in Bayme.sh Home on Bayme.sh</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bayme.sh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/overview/</guid><description>What more of an overview do people need? ChatGPT was here.
Meshtastic is an open-source project that allows people to communicate over long distances without relying on traditional cellular networks or Wi-Fi. It uses affordable devices equipped with LoRa (Long Range) technology to create a mesh network, enabling text messaging and GPS location sharing even in remote areas. Ideal for outdoor adventures, emergency situations, and local events, Meshtastic provides a simple and reliable way to stay connected when other communication methods are unavailable.</description></item><item><title>FAQ's</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/faq/</guid><description>Q - I send messages but don&amp;rsquo;t get an ack/response?
A - In order to get an acknowledgement from your message, there must be another node in range. Here&amp;rsquo;s a few tips to help out:
Check the maps, to see if there are any nodes close to you on the map. Within a few miles at most. Remember that not all nodes are reported on the map and the nodes on the map may be old.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Net</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/weekly-net/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/weekly-net/</guid><description>Wednesday at 5pm. On air and on Discord voice
Meshtastic Net I will keep it open from 5-6pm for checkins so you do not have to rush. The message format will just be (LONG NAME) - (CITY YOU ARE IN) #BayMeshNet. So for example I would do Ko6cnt Base - Santa Clara #BayMeshNet.
Voice Call Also at the same time at 5pm we will be holding a voice call in the discord voice channel.</description></item><item><title>Emergency/Private Use</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/emergency-private-use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/emergency-private-use/</guid><description>If you are planning on using Meshtastic in the Bay Area and don&amp;rsquo;t want to participate in the broader network, or what to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re setup with your friends/family in case of an emergency, that&amp;rsquo;s cool. We&amp;rsquo;ve got some suggestions for you:
Don&amp;rsquo;t use Frequency Slot 0 Use &amp;ldquo;client&amp;rdquo; mode</description></item><item><title>Licensed Operations</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/licensed-operations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/licensed-operations/</guid><description>See the offical docs on Amateur Radio
In short, you can transmit up to 10W with high gain antennas. On the flip side you cannot join the default mesh and encryption must be (and is automatically) disabled.</description></item><item><title>Other Community Resources</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/community-docs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/community-docs/</guid><description> What&amp;rsquo;s so fantastic about Meshtastic? by KO6CNT - Presented to PAARA on June 6, 2024 Meshtastic @ Benicia Amateur Radio Club by KJ6FNQ Jon Davis. Meshtastic &amp;ldquo;Pitch&amp;rdquo; Deck by KJ6FNQ Jon Davis - Basics used for other presontation and in person events such as Maker Faire.</description></item><item><title>OpenSauce 2024 Retrospective</title><link>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/07/01/opensauce-2024-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/07/01/opensauce-2024-retrospective/</guid><description>The Meshtastic Booth OpenSauce 2024 was amazing! And, oh boy, was it exhausting. It took our team a little time to recover before we had the energy to write up this recap of the incredible event and the awesome community interest in Meshtastic.
What is OpenSauce? Well, if names like Mark Rober, Colin Furze, The Hacksmith, and Wren from Corridor Digital ring a bell, then you might already get the vibe.</description></item><item><title>Meshtastic on Balloon (Update - Splashed down)</title><link>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/09/meshtastic-on-balloon-update-splashed-down/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/09/meshtastic-on-balloon-update-splashed-down/</guid><description>Update: Last data recieved at 12:47 and the balloon was falling. The balloon is assumed to have gone into the bay.
We&amp;rsquo;ve got Meshtastic on Ballon. Tune in to voice on discord live (as of 11am).
Useful Links: https://meshview.armooo.net/packet_list/862482136?q=!33686ed8&amp;portnum= https://meshtastic.liamcottle.net/?lat=37.99120560871103&amp;lng=237.66453266143802&amp;zoom=16 https://data.bayme.sh/balloon https://aprs.fi/#!call=a%2FW6MRR-9&amp;timerange=3600&amp;tail=3600 Ham Cross band repeater Input Frequency: 445.525 MHz PL Frequency : -162.2 MHz Output Frequency: 145.25 MHz</description></item><item><title>Introducing the New Meshtastic Bay Area Website</title><link>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/08/introducing-the-new-meshtastic-bay-area-website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/08/introducing-the-new-meshtastic-bay-area-website/</guid><description>We are excited to announce the launch of our brand-new Meshtastic Bay Area website! This project has been a labor of love, designed to bring our community closer together and provide a centralized hub for all things related to Meshtastic in the San Francisco Bay Area. Here’s a rundown of what you can expect from our new site:
Key Features: User-Friendly Design: Our website features a clean, intuitive layout, making it easy to navigate and find the information you need.</description></item><item><title>Join us at OpenSauce 2024</title><link>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/06/join-us-at-opensauce-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/06/join-us-at-opensauce-2024/</guid><description>We are thrilled to invite you to OpenSauce 2024, the world&amp;rsquo;s biggest gathering of makers, creators, and technology innovators, happening from June 14-16 at the Cow Palace in San Francisco. This exciting event will feature over 500 creators and makers showcasing their cutting-edge tech, wild experiments, and interactive exhibits. OpenSauce is a must-attend for anyone who loves to see the boundaries of creativity and innovation pushed to the limit.
This year marks the first official showing of Meshtastic at a conference or event, and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more excited!</description></item><item><title>Meshtastic Basics</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/meshtastic-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/meshtastic-basics/</guid><description>This was generated by ChatGPT. Someone should make sure its legit before trusting anything.
Introduction to Meshtastic Meshtastic is an open-source project that enables long-range, low-power, mesh communication using inexpensive hardware. It is primarily designed for outdoor activities, emergency scenarios, and other use cases where traditional communication infrastructure is unavailable.
Core Components Hardware
LoRa Modules: Meshtastic uses LoRa (Long Range) modules, which are capable of transmitting data over several kilometers using minimal power.</description></item><item><title>MQTT</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/mqtt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/mqtt/</guid><description>This is on the most advanced side of things. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what &amp;ldquo;MQTT&amp;rdquo; is, leave it disabled. You do not need to turn MQTT to have your messages on the logger.
This is also only useful on &amp;ldquo;base station&amp;rdquo; nodes. Ones that are in a good position to pick up messages AND with a stable internet/wifi connection.
MQTT is the technology used to feed the mesh data to the internet (aka what powers the Mesh Maps, Discord Logger, etc).</description></item><item><title>Recommended Hardware</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/recommended-hardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/recommended-hardware/</guid><description>See also Discord #resources thread
SeeedStudio Tracker T1000-E The T1000-E by SeeedStudio is one of the few “ready to go” out of the box nodes available with a ~2 day battery life and integrated GPS. It is IP65 and approximately the size of a credit card (but thicker). These features and its low cost make it an excellent starter unit for first time Meshtastic users.
Pros Long battery life (2+ days) GPS &amp;amp; Battery Included ~$40 USD IP65 case Cons No support for external antenna Rak Wisblock The WisBlock is the “Lego” of Meshtastic nodes.</description></item><item><title>Recommended Settings</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/recommended-settings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/recommended-settings/</guid><description>Please make sure to update the firmware on your device as you get started. The easiest way to do that is to use the Web Flasher. The latest stable release, even if labeled Beta, is generally a very safe option.
Most importantly make sure to keep all automatic beacons like telemetry and position (if used on a stationary node) to 1 hour +.
If you are joining our Medium Slow network you can fill out the optional registration Google Form</description></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>https://bayme.sh/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>