<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bayme.sh Home on Bayme.sh</title><link>https://bayme.sh/</link><description>Recent content in Bayme.sh Home on Bayme.sh</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bayme.sh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/overview/</guid><description>What more of an overview do people need? ChatGPT was here.
Meshtastic is an open-source project that allows people to communicate over long distances without relying on traditional cellular networks or Wi-Fi. It uses affordable devices equipped with LoRa (Long Range) technology to create a mesh network, enabling text messaging and GPS location sharing even in remote areas. Ideal for outdoor adventures, emergency situations, and local events, Meshtastic provides a simple and reliable way to stay connected when other communication methods are unavailable.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Net</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/weekly-net/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/weekly-net/</guid><description>Wednesday at 5pm. On air and on Discord voice
Meshtastic Net I will keep it open from 5-6pm for checkins so you do not have to rush. The message format will just be (LONG NAME) - (CITY YOU ARE IN) #BayMeshNet. So for example I would do Ko6cnt Base - Santa Clara #BayMeshNet.
Voice Call Also at the same time at 5pm we will be holding a voice call in the discord voice channel.</description></item><item><title>Emergency/Private Use</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/emergency-private-use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/emergency-private-use/</guid><description>If you are planning on using Meshtastic in the Bay Area and don&amp;rsquo;t want to participate in the broader network, or what to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re setup with your friends/family in case of an emergency, that&amp;rsquo;s cool. We&amp;rsquo;ve got some suggestions for you:
Don&amp;rsquo;t use Frequency Slot 0 Use &amp;ldquo;client&amp;rdquo; mode</description></item><item><title>Other Community Resources</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/community-docs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/community-docs/</guid><description> What&amp;rsquo;s so fantastic about Meshtastic? by KO6CNT - Presented to PAARA on June 6, 2024</description></item><item><title>Introducing the New Meshtastic Bay Area Website</title><link>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/08/introducing-the-new-meshtastic-bay-area-website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/08/introducing-the-new-meshtastic-bay-area-website/</guid><description>We are excited to announce the launch of our brand-new Meshtastic Bay Area website! This project has been a labor of love, designed to bring our community closer together and provide a centralized hub for all things related to Meshtastic in the San Francisco Bay Area. Here’s a rundown of what you can expect from our new site:
Key Features: User-Friendly Design: Our website features a clean, intuitive layout, making it easy to navigate and find the information you need.</description></item><item><title>Join us at OpenSauce 2024</title><link>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/06/join-us-at-opensauce-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/06/join-us-at-opensauce-2024/</guid><description>We are thrilled to invite you to OpenSauce 2024, the world&amp;rsquo;s biggest gathering of makers, creators, and technology innovators, happening from June 14-16 at the Cow Palace in San Francisco. This exciting event will feature over 500 creators and makers showcasing their cutting-edge tech, wild experiments, and interactive exhibits. OpenSauce is a must-attend for anyone who loves to see the boundaries of creativity and innovation pushed to the limit.
This year marks the first official showing of Meshtastic at a conference or event, and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more excited!</description></item><item><title>Meshtastic Basics</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/meshtastic-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/meshtastic-basics/</guid><description>This was generated by ChatGPT. Someone should make sure its legit before trusting anything.
Introduction to Meshtastic Meshtastic is an open-source project that enables long-range, low-power, mesh communication using inexpensive hardware. It is primarily designed for outdoor activities, emergency scenarios, and other use cases where traditional communication infrastructure is unavailable.
Core Components Hardware
LoRa Modules: Meshtastic uses LoRa (Long Range) modules, which are capable of transmitting data over several kilometers using minimal power.</description></item><item><title>MQTT</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/mqtt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/mqtt/</guid><description> Don&amp;rsquo;t enable MQTT Downlink Use msh/US/bayarea topic Beware that RAK don&amp;rsquo;t support JSON</description></item><item><title>Recommended Hardware</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/recommended-hardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/recommended-hardware/</guid><description>See also Discord #resources thread
Rak Wisblock Pros Low power usage Modular (Can easily add on gps and sensors) Dedicated solar input Cons Requires assembly Order from Rak Wireless Rokland Etsy Amazon T Beam Pros Fully built with display and gps (except battery and case) Reliable Somewhat cheap Cons High power usage Weird antenna placement Order from Lilygo Rokland Etsy Amazon TTGo Lora Pros Small form factor Cheap Already attached display and built in wifi and ble antenna Cons No gps High battery usage Order from Lilygo Rokland Amazon Wis Mesh Pros battery efficient Integrated gps Nicest form factor Fully built with case Cons A bit expensive Order from Rak Wireless Rokland</description></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>https://bayme.sh/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>