<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started on Bayme.sh</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on Bayme.sh</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Meshtastic Basics</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/meshtastic-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/meshtastic-basics/</guid><description>This was generated by ChatGPT. Someone should make sure its legit before trusting anything.
Introduction to Meshtastic Meshtastic is an open-source project that enables long-range, low-power, mesh communication using inexpensive hardware. It is primarily designed for outdoor activities, emergency scenarios, and other use cases where traditional communication infrastructure is unavailable.
Core Components Hardware
LoRa Modules: Meshtastic uses LoRa (Long Range) modules, which are capable of transmitting data over several kilometers using minimal power.</description></item><item><title>MQTT</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/mqtt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/mqtt/</guid><description>This is on the most advanced side of things. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what &amp;ldquo;MQTT&amp;rdquo; is, leave it disabled. You do not need to turn MQTT to have your messages on the logger.
This is also only useful on &amp;ldquo;base station&amp;rdquo; nodes. Ones that are in a good position to pick up messages AND with a stable internet/wifi connection.
MQTT is the technology used to feed the mesh data to the internet (aka what powers the Mesh Maps, Discord Logger, etc).</description></item><item><title>Recommended Hardware</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/recommended-hardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/recommended-hardware/</guid><description>See also Discord #resources thread
Rak Wisblock Pros Low power usage Modular (Can easily add on gps and sensors) Dedicated solar input Cons Requires assembly Order from Rak Wireless Rokland Etsy Amazon T Beam Pros Fully built with display and gps (except battery and case) Reliable Somewhat cheap Cons High power usage Weird antenna placement Order from Lilygo Rokland Etsy Amazon TTGo Lora Pros Small form factor Cheap Already attached display and built in wifi and ble antenna Cons No gps High battery usage Order from Lilygo Rokland Amazon Wis Mesh Pros battery efficient Integrated gps Nicest form factor Fully built with case Cons A bit expensive Order from Rak Wireless Rokland</description></item><item><title>Recommended Settings</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/recommended-settings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/getting-started/recommended-settings/</guid><description>Please make sure to update the firmware on your device as you get started. The easiest way to do that is to use the Web Flasher. The latest stable release, even if labeled Beta, is generally a very safe option.
Most importantly make sure to keep all automatic beacons like telemetry and position (if used on a stationary node) to 1 hour +.
In the Bay Area, we have a few recommendations for configuration:</description></item></channel></rss>