<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News &amp; Events on Bayme.sh</title><link>https://bayme.sh/blog/</link><description>Recent content in News &amp; Events on Bayme.sh</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bayme.sh/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing the New Meshtastic Bay Area Website</title><link>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/08/introducing-the-new-meshtastic-bay-area-website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/08/introducing-the-new-meshtastic-bay-area-website/</guid><description>We are excited to announce the launch of our brand-new Meshtastic Bay Area website! This project has been a labor of love, designed to bring our community closer together and provide a centralized hub for all things related to Meshtastic in the San Francisco Bay Area. Here’s a rundown of what you can expect from our new site:
Key Features: User-Friendly Design: Our website features a clean, intuitive layout, making it easy to navigate and find the information you need.</description></item><item><title>Join us at OpenSauce 2024</title><link>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/06/join-us-at-opensauce-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/blog/2024/06/06/join-us-at-opensauce-2024/</guid><description>We are thrilled to invite you to OpenSauce 2024, the world&amp;rsquo;s biggest gathering of makers, creators, and technology innovators, happening from June 14-16 at the Cow Palace in San Francisco. This exciting event will feature over 500 creators and makers showcasing their cutting-edge tech, wild experiments, and interactive exhibits. OpenSauce is a must-attend for anyone who loves to see the boundaries of creativity and innovation pushed to the limit.
This year marks the first official showing of Meshtastic at a conference or event, and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more excited!</description></item></channel></rss>