<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation &amp; Resources on Bayme.sh</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation &amp; Resources on Bayme.sh</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://bayme.sh/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/overview/</guid><description>What more of an overview do people need? ChatGPT was here.
Meshtastic is an open-source project that allows people to communicate over long distances without relying on traditional cellular networks or Wi-Fi. It uses affordable devices equipped with LoRa (Long Range) technology to create a mesh network, enabling text messaging and GPS location sharing even in remote areas. Ideal for outdoor adventures, emergency situations, and local events, Meshtastic provides a simple and reliable way to stay connected when other communication methods are unavailable.</description></item><item><title>FAQ's</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/faq/</guid><description>Q - I send messages but don&amp;rsquo;t get an ack/response?
A - In order to get an acknowledgement from your message, there must be another node in range. Here&amp;rsquo;s a few tips to help out:
Check the maps, to see if there are any nodes close to you on the map. Within a few miles at most. Remember that not all nodes are reported on the map and the nodes on the map may be old.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Net</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/weekly-net/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/weekly-net/</guid><description>Wednesday at 5pm. On air and on Discord voice
Meshtastic Net I will keep it open from 5-6pm for checkins so you do not have to rush. The message format will just be (LONG NAME) - (CITY YOU ARE IN) #BayMeshNet. So for example I would do Ko6cnt Base - Santa Clara #BayMeshNet.
Voice Call Also at the same time at 5pm we will be holding a voice call in the discord voice channel.</description></item><item><title>Emergency/Private Use</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/emergency-private-use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/emergency-private-use/</guid><description>If you are planning on using Meshtastic in the Bay Area and don&amp;rsquo;t want to participate in the broader network, or what to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re setup with your friends/family in case of an emergency, that&amp;rsquo;s cool. We&amp;rsquo;ve got some suggestions for you:
Don&amp;rsquo;t use Frequency Slot 0 Use &amp;ldquo;client&amp;rdquo; mode</description></item><item><title>Licensed Operations</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/licensed-operations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/licensed-operations/</guid><description>See the offical docs on Amateur Radio
In short, you can transmit up to 10W with high gain antennas. On the flip side you cannot join the default mesh and encryption must be (and is automatically) disabled.</description></item><item><title>Other Community Resources</title><link>https://bayme.sh/docs/community-docs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bayme.sh/docs/community-docs/</guid><description> What&amp;rsquo;s so fantastic about Meshtastic? by KO6CNT - Presented to PAARA on June 6, 2024 Meshtastic @ Benicia Amateur Radio Club by KJ6FNQ Jon Davis. Meshtastic &amp;ldquo;Pitch&amp;rdquo; Deck by KJ6FNQ Jon Davis - Basics used for other presontation and in person events such as Maker Faire.</description></item></channel></rss>